Hello, I'm Kyle Brayer, and you're next in-home abdominal work out is the scissor kick.
The scissor kick is performed on a mat.
You can do it at home or in the gym.
Kerry's going to lay back for us, on to her back.
She's going to slide her hands palm down, under her glutes.
This is her starting position.
She'll stick her legs straight out, and she's going to try to stay in line, from her hips all the way up to her neck is going to stay flat.
She's going to try not to move her neck left or right, and she's going to try and lock her upper torso.
From here, she's going to lift her feet off the ground about three inches, and that will be her next starting position.
And she's just going to alternate legs up and down.
That's a scissor kick.
So, here she's pointing her toes.
A variation is for her to flex her foot, so she's going to pull her toe back toward her knee.
This is going to add a little more pull on the lower abdominal region.
OK, and stop, and down.
And notice when Kerry performs this exercise, that her shoulders, her hips, and her arms stay perfectly still.
She's breathing in through her nose and our through her mouth for the duration of the exercise.
And this really isolates the bottoms portion of the abs.
So, one more time Kerry.
The legs come up, and then she alternates up and down.
And relax.
And that exercise is the scissor kick.